Pavel Kirilin

Software Developer / Moscow, Russia

Email: kirilin.pav@gmail.com / LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/pkirilin / GitHub: https://github.com/pkirilin

Summary

Software developer with 4+ years of experience mainly on the .NET stack and knowledge of modern frontend technologies (React, Angular). For the last couple of years have been developing integration REST APIs based on cloud solutions (Microsoft Azure). Also developed small APIs and scripts using Node.js.

Skills

C# | .NET 6 | ASP.NET Core | Entity Framework Core | MySQL | PostgreSQL | Docker HTML | CSS | JavaScript | TypeScript | React | Redux | Node.js | ExpressJS

Experience

Dodo Engineering / https://dodobrands.io / Moscow, Russia

IT part of Dodo Brands - an international foodservice group developing a portfolio of digital-first QSR brands (Dodo Pizza, Drinklt, Doner42), its main product is a cloud information system for managing all Dodo business (Dodo IS).

Developer (Jan 2021 - Present)

- Designed, documented and developed 6 public API endpoints to be used by external developers.
- Developed MVP of Dodo IS Marketplace service, which is going to be used to integrate 2 third-party applications with the company's information system and extend its capabilities.
- Developed a support bot for automating the daily work of the technical support team, which made it more efficient and increased the support SLA by 8% despite the 32% incoming ticket growth.
- Automated the gathering of the support statistics metrics from 2 third-party SaaS services into the dashboard, which is saving 2-3 days per week for 2nd line support managers.

Stack: .NET 6, ASP.NET Core, Entity Framework Core, Angular 12, Docker, GitHub Actions, Kubernetes, Microsoft Azure.

Super Brands / http://www.superbrands.ru / Moscow, Russia

A distributor of more than 12 world brands of clothing, footwear and accessories for over 15 retailers.

Backend developer (Jul 2019 - Oct 2020)

Developed the backend part of the information system, which automates processes of wholesale trade for clothes, shoes and accessories using a microservice approach with Domain-Driven Design.

- Reworked existing integration with the internal accounting system in processing orders and switched exchange from SOAP to REST.
- Reworked existing system's import/export functionality for products in excel format.
- Developed 1 microservice for working with addresses (address book equivalent).

Stack: .NET Core 3.1, ASP.NET Core, Entity Framework Core, PostgreSQL, git, GitLab CI/CD, Jira, Slack.

Quorum / Moscow, Russia

An integrator with 20 years of history, provides IT solutions for over 40 financial institutions.

Junior developer (Nov 2018 - Jun 2019)

• Developed the application for automating the banking loan pipeline.

Stack: .NET Framework, ASP.NET, WCF, JavaScript, Oracle, PostgreSQL, NHibernate, Castle Windsor, TeamCity, Jira.

Education

Bauman Moscow State Technical University / https://www.bmstu.ru / Moscow, Russia

Bachelor of Applied Science (Sep 2014 - Jun 2018)

Robotics and Complex Automation, Computer-Aided Design and Engineering.

Additional information

- Languages: Russian (native), English (upper-Intermediate)
- Citizenship: Russian Federation